Guide to the Hapgood Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1893-1977; Series III; 9.5; (23 boxes)
  - NEITH BOYCE HAPGOOD
    - Shorter Works
      - Short Stories
        - "The Eternal Flame"
          - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1224)
          - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1225)
        - "The Faithful Wife": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1226)
        - "Fantasy"
          - Draft A, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1227)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1228)
        - "The Fickle Sex"
          - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1229)
          - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1230)
        - "The Fieldmouse": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1231)
        - "The Flights of Mr. Doe"
          - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1232)
          - Printed version, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1233)
        - "The Flower of Rajisthan": printed version, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1234)
        - "The Flute-Player"
          - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1235)
          - Draft B, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1236)
        - "Fool's Gold"
          - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1237)
          - Draft fragments, holograph, parts I-II, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1238-39)
        - "For Lack of Rain": printed version, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1240)
        - "The Forbidden City"
          - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1241)
          - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1242)
        - "The Fount of Learning": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1243)
        - "Freedom!": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1244)
        - "The French Are So Rude"
          - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1245)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1246)
          - Draft fragments, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1247)
        - "Gamble"
          - Draft A, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1248)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1249)
          - Draft fragments, holograph, and typescript, part I-IV (Box 41, Folder 1250-53)
        - "The Ghost of Cramley": draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1254)
        - "The Green Bay Tree": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1255)
        - "Happiness": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1256)
        - "His Ducats and His Daughter": printed version, 1908 Sep (Box 41, Folder 1257)
        - "In the Fair Land of Dreams": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 41, Folder 1258)
        - "Inferiors": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1259)
        - "The Intervention of San Pedro": printed version, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1260)
        - "The Invasion of Eden"
          - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1261)
          - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1262)
        - "The Land of Beginnings"
          - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1263)
          - Draft B, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1264)
          - Draft fragments, holograph, and typescript (Box 41, Folder 1265)
        - "The Last Cruise": printed version, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1266)
        - "The Last Frontier": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1267)
        - "The Legacy": printed version, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1268)
        - "Lestrange": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1269)
        - "The Lie": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1270)
        - "Life"
          - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1271)
          - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1272)
        - "A Little Comedy of Manners": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1273)
        - "A Livelier Plumage": printed version, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1274)
        - "Luxury": printed version, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1275)
        - "Maddalena Speaks": printed version, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1276)
        - "Maescenas"
          - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1277)
          - Draft B, typescript and carbon (Box 41, Folder 1278)
        - "Mama"
          - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1279)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1280)
        - "Man Proposes": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1281)
        - "The Man's League": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1282)
        - "Maruska"
          - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1283)
          - Draft fragments, holograph and typescript (Box 42, Folder 1284)
        - "The Measure of His Youth": draft, holograph, corrected, parts I-II, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1285-86)
        - [Mersylvia Bowles]: draft fragments, typescript and carbon, parts I-III (Box 42, Folder 1287-89)
        - "The Model Wife": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1290)
        - "Navidad": printed version (incomplete), n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1291)
        - "Night Piece"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1292)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1293)
        - "The Nurse": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1294)
        - "Off the Earth"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1295)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1296)
        - "Old Glory": draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1297)
        - "Palimpsest": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1298)
        - "The Picture of Marie": printed version, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1299)
        - "A Player": printed version, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1300)
        - "A Portrait": printed version, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1301)
        - "Post Mortem"
          - Outline, holograph, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1302)
          - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1303)
        - "A Provident Woman": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 42, Folder 1304)
        - "The Red Letter": printed version (incomplete), n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1305)
        - "The Reformation": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 42, Folder 1306)
        - "Retreat": printed version, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1307)
        - "Return"
          Part I
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1308)
          - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1309)
          - Part II
          - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1310)
          - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1311)
          - Draft fragments, holograph and typescript, parts I-II (Box 42, Folder 1312-13)
        - "The Rider": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1314)
        - "The Rights of Man"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1315)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1316)
        - "Roses"
          - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1317)
          - Printed version, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1318)
        - "Sand"
          - Draft A, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1319)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1320)
          - Draft fragments, holograph and typescript, parts I-III (Box 43, Folder 1321-23)
        - "Sauce for the Goose"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1324-25)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1326)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1327)
          - Draft D, typescript, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1328)
          - Draft E, typescript, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1329)
          - Draft fragments, holograph and typescript (Box 43, Folder 1330)
        - "The Scapegoat": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1331-32)
        - "The Shadow of the Sea": outline, holograph, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1333)
        - "The Shuttlecock": printed version, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1334)
        - "Silence is Gold": printed version, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1335)
        - "Spanish Interlude": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1336)
        - "Speed": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1337)
        - "The State": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1338)
        - "A Straw for a Day": draft, typescript and carbon (Box 43, Folder 1339)
        - "Theresa": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1340)
        - "Three Men": draft, holograph (Box 43, Folder 1341)
        - "The Threshold"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, 1915 (Box 43, Folder 1342)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1915 (Box 43, Folder 1343)
        - "Thrift"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1344)
          - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1345)
        - "The Town's Affair": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1346)
        - "Two Women"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1347)
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1348)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1349)
          - Draft C, typescript, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1350)
        - "Uncle Christopher": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1351)
        - "The Undertow"
          - Outline, holograph, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1352)
          - Printed version, 1914 Aug (Box 44, Folder 1353)
        - "The Unequal Yoke": printed version, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1354)
        - "The Vanity Bag": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1355)
        - "Vespa"
          - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1356)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1357)
        - "The Vestals": printed version, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1358)
        - "Una Vieja": printed version, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1359)
        - "Villa Curonia"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1360)
          - Draft B, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1361)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1362)
        - "Villa Scifanoja"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, parts I-III, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1363-65)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1366-67)
        - "Why?": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1368)
        - Unidentified
          - Draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1369)
          - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1370-72)
          - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1373-74)
          - Printed version, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1375)
        - Miscellaneous draft fragments, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1376-79)
        - Miscellaneous research notes, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1380-82)
- Family Papers, 1829-1951; Series IV; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series IV, Family Papers (Boxes 45-47), is divided into seven subseries, Business Papers, Diaries, Maps, Photographs, Subject Files, Writings of Others, and Miscellaneous Papers. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically arranged.
  - BUSINESS PAPERS
    - Business Papers, 1878-1944, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1383-86)
  - DIARIES
    - Diary of Hutchins Hapgood, 1926 (Box 45, Folder 1387)
    - Diaries of Neith Boyce Hapgood
      - Italy, 1903 (Box 45, Folder 1388)
      - Italy (transcription), 1903 (Box 45, Folder 1389)
      - Italy, 1914 (Box 45, Folder 1390)
      - Farm diary, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1391)
    - Dialogue of Hutchins and Neith Boyce Hapgood: holograph and typescript, carbon (Box 45, Folder 1392)
  - MAPS
    See also: Oversize, Box 48, folders 1539-40
    - Map of farm [near Bridgewater, Conn.], n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1393)
    - Map of plot of land: holograph (Box 45, Folder 1394)
    - Map of Richmond, New Hampshire (Box 45, Folder 1395)
    - Print of farm house, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1396)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Beach, Mr., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1397)
    - Berenson, Bernard, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1398)
    - Bonnell, Margaret Boyce, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1399)
    - Boyce, baby girl (one of Neith's sisters who died (?)), n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1400)
    - Bright, Edward Hamilton, Family of (Edward Hamilton, Miriam Hapgood, and Ned) (Box 45, Folder 1401)
    - Cook, George Cram, Family of (George Cram, Susan Glaspell, and Nilla Cook), ca. 1922 (Box 45, Folder 1402)
    - Faust, Luke H., Family of (Luke H., Beatrix Hapgood, Luke, and Neith Boyce) (Box 45, Folder 1403)
    - Hapgood, Brutus Caesar Augustus Napoleon Bonaparte, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1404)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917), n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1405)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), Family of (Charles Hutchins (1904-82), Tamsin, and Fred) (Box 45, Folder 1406)
    - Hapgood, Eleanor Page, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1407)
    - Hapgood, Fannie Louise Collins Powers, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1408)
    - Hapgood, Harry Boyce
      See: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1541
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1409)
      See also: Oversize, Box 48, folders 1541-42
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, Children of (Harry Boyce, Charles Hutchins (1904-82), Miriam, and Beatrix) (Box 45, Folder 1410)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce, Grandchildren of (Box 45, Folder 1411)
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1412)
      See also: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1542
    - Hapgood, Seth, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1413)
    - Hapgood, William Powers; Hapgood, Powers; Hapgood, Harry Boyce; and Operhaltzer (?) (Box 45, Folder 1414)
    - Houses, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1415)
    - Keanley, Dr., n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1416)
    - O'Brien, Joe
      See: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1542
    - Richmond, New Hampshire: farm house (Box 45, Folder 1417)
    - Steffens, Lincoln and Pete Stanley (Box 46, Folder 1418)
    - Taos, New Mexico: Taos Mountain, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1419)
    - Taos, New Mexico: churches, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1420)
    - Trianovitch, Vaso, Family of (Vaso, Miriam Hapgood, Ned Bright, and Tim Bright) (Box 46, Folder 1421)
    - Wheeler, Bull with ox-team, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1422)
    - Wimsey, Peter, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1423)
    - Unidentified young woman holding puppy [Fanny Hess (?)], ca. 1890s (Box 46, Folder 1424)
    - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1425)
    - Negatives, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1426)
    - Postcards, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1427)
  - SUBJECT FILES
    - Bonnell, Alice Harrison: poems, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1428)
    - Bonnell, Bayard Henry: poems, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1429)
    - Boyce, Charles, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1430)
    - Boyce, Helen Faith
      - Poems, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1431)
      - Wedding invitation, 1912 Sep 27 (Box 46, Folder 1432)
    - Boyce, Henry Harrison
      - Biographical sketch, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1433)
      - Copy of letter from M. D. Leggett to [Richard Yates?], 1864 Dec 28 (Box 46, Folder 1433a)
      - Obituaries, 1903-04 (Box 46, Folder 1434)
    - The Columbia Conserve Company: tomato soup can label, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1435)
    - DeWitt, Miriam Hapgood
      Marriage to Edward Hamilton Bright
      - Publicity, 1930 Oct 6 (Box 46, Folder 1436)
      - Wedding invitation, 1930 Sep 30 (Box 46, Folder 1437)
      - Poems, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1438)
    - Drawings by various family members, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1439)
      See also: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1543
    - Faust, Beatrix Hapgood
      - Poems, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1440)
      - Report card, 1927-38 (Box 46, Folder 1441)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917)
      - Business cards [as attorney], n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1442)
      - Calling cards, 1911-15 (Box 46, Folder 1443)
      - Will, 1916 May 31 (Box 46, Folder 1444)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1836-1917) and Fanny Louise Collins Powers
      - Italy, List of places visited in, ca. 1913 (Box 46, Folder 1445)
      - Joint wedding invitation of the above couple and golden wedding anniversary announcement of her grandparents, Reuben L. and Fanny Louise Collins Hess, 1867 May 14 (Box 46, Folder 1446)
      - Will, Joint, 1913 Aug 5 (Box 46, Folder 1447)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82)
      - General, 1937-46, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1448)
      - Poems, 1918-20, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1449)
      - Prose compositions, 1914, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1450-51)
    - Hapgood, Charles Hutchins (1904-82); Faust, Beatrix Hapgood; and Dewitt, Miriam Hapgood: "Poems and Drawings": printed version, 1929 Dec (Box 46, Folder 1452)
    - Hapgood, Emilie Bigelow, 1914 Nov 12 (Box 46, Folder 1453)
    - Hapgood, Emma Frances
      See also: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1544
      - Calling card, 1903 (Box 46, Folder 1454)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1455)
    - Hapgood, Fanny Louise Collins Powers
      - Calling card, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1456)
      - "Charles' Description of Ruth's Doll House", n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1457)
      - Instructions re disposition of physical remains, 1915 Jan 22 (Box 46, Folder 1458)
      - Will, copy, 1917 May 3 (Box 46, Folder 1459)
    - Hapgood, Harry Boyce
      - Prose compositions, 1910-17, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1460)
      - "Souvenir Folder Illustrating in Colors Cowboy Life in the Northwest", 1914 (Box 46, Folder 1461)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins
      - Address book, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1462)
      - Articles about, 1912-17, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1463)
      - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1464)
      - Eugene Field Society: certificate of honorary membership, 1941 Jan 30 (Box 46, Folder 1465)
      - European Relief Council: certificate, 1921 Jan 5 (Box 46, Folder 1466)
      - Friedrich-Wilhelm-Universität (Berlin): course registration booklet, 1894 (Box 46, Folder 1467)
      - Harvard University, Publicity on graduation from, ca. 1892 (Box 46, Folder 1468)
        See also: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1545
      - Lectures: brochures, 1915-19, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1469)
      - Obituaries, 1944 Nov (Box 46, Folder 1470)
      - Passport, 1926 Oct 18 (Box 46, Folder 1471)
      - Tombstone, Information on, 1945 May 16 (Box 46, Folder 1472)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins and Neith Boyce: wedding invitation, 1899 Jun 22 (Box 46, Folder 1473)
    - Hapgood, Lydia Seaver Wilson: calling card, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1474)
    - Hapgood, Lydia Seaver Wilson and Emma Frances: Florida trip, Receipts and miscellany from, 1878, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1475)
    - Hapgood, Neith Boyce
      - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1476)
      - Daybook entries (loose), 1926-27 (Box 47, Folder 1477)
      - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1478)
      - Notebook, 1909-16 (Box 47, Folder 1479)
      - Obituary, 1951 Dec 3 (Box 47, Folder 1480)
      - Prose compositions relating to the death of Harry Boyce Hapgood, 1919, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1481)
      - Will, Codicil to, 1938 Oct 8 (Box 47, Folder 1482)
      - Will, draft, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1483)
    - Hapgood, Nellie, 1871 Jun 9 (Box 47, Folder 1484)
    - Hapgood, Norman
      - Articles about, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1485)
      - Biographical materials, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1486)
      - Calling card, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1487)
    - Hapgood, Norman, Jr. and Ruth Gillmore: wedding invitation, 1944 Jul 19 (Box 47, Folder 1488)
    - Hapgood, Powers, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1489)
    - Hapgood, Ruth (1880-90): obituary, 1890 Mar 29 (Box 47, Folder 1490)
    - Hapgood, Seth
      - Biographical sketch, 1864 Apr 1 (Box 47, Folder 1491)
      - Daybook, 1829-30 (Box 47, Folder 1492)
      - Financial Papers, Miscellaneous, 1861-62, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1493)
      - Pocket diary, 1857 (Box 47, Folder 1494)
    - Japan: itinerary, ca. 1898 (Box 47, Folder 1495)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge: book reviews of Movers and Shakers, 1936-38, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1496)
      See also: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1546
    - Medical records of various family members, 1912-43, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1497)
    - Petersham, Massachusetts, Village of
      - General, 1854-80 (Box 47, Folder 1498)
      - Names of volunteers belonging to the "Petersham Company" in the Civil War, 1862 Sep (Box 47, Folder 1499)
    - Play by unidentified family member, 1911 Oct 22 (Box 47, Folder 1500)
    - Poems by unidentified family members, 1928, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1501)
    - Reklaitis, Elizabeth Boyce: poems, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1502)
    - Sculptors, 1915-37 (Box 47, Folder 1503)
    - Travelogue: Saltillo-Mexico City, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1504)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Boyce, Mary E., Outlines of the History, Art, and Literature of Greece, 1894 (Box 47, Folder 1505)
    - Butler, Frank, Poems: advertisement, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1506)
    - Davis Earl C., Letter to the Editor [i.e., Norman Hapgood]: printed version, 1936 May 21 (Box 47, Folder 1507)
    - Hapgood, Norman
      - The Advancing Hour: outline, typescript, corrected, 1920 (Box 47, Folder 1508)
      - Book review of The Letters of Sacco and Vanzetti: printed version (Box 47, Folder 1509)
      - "The Intellectual Parvenue": printed version in The Chap-Book, pp. 553-59, 1896 May 1 (Box 47, Folder 1510)
      - "Normal Hapgood's Weekly Letter": printed version, 1927 Mar 22 (Box 47, Folder 1511)
      - Transcript, Radio Program #3, 1933 (?) Oct 25 (Box 47, Folder 1512)
    - Hapgood, Powers
      - "A Boston Jury Surprises": printed version in The Lantern, p. 7, 1928 Jan (Box 47, Folder 1513)
      - "Journal": draft, typescript, 1924-25 (Box 47, Folder 1514)
      - "Men and Coal": draft, typescript (Box 47, Folder 1515)
    - Hornibrook, F. A., "Rolling the Abdominal Wall": printed version, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1516)
    - Killingbeck, Wilson B., "Hutchins Hapgood and the Socialists": printed version (Box 47, Folder 1517)
    - Lovett, Robert Morss, "The Ethical Paradox in Shelley": printed version, 1922 Jul 19 (Box 47, Folder 1518)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge
      - Letter to the Editor [re Hutchins Hapgood]: printed version, 1913 (Box 47, Folder 1519)
      - Translation of Latin prophesy made in 1600 by the monk Johannes: typescript and carbon (Box 47, Folder 1520)
    - Marriner, Gerald, "Hutchins Hapgood: The Story of a Lover": draft, typescript, photocopy, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 1521)
    - Moehlman, Arthur B., "Mad or Muddled?": printed version, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1522)
    - Reed, Herbert, "Sports": printed version, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1523)
    - Steffens, Lincoln, "John Reed under the Kremlin": printed version, 1921 (Box 47, Folder 1524)
    - Unidentified
      - Draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1525)
      - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1526)
      - Printed version, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1527)
  - MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1883-1942, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1528)
      See also: Oversize, Box 48, folder 1547
- 2006 Addition, 1911-2000; Series V; 0.42; (1 box) + 2 broadsides
  Series V. 2006 Addition consists chiefly or material by or relating to Elizabeth Reynolds Hapgood. Material is divided into two suberies, Writings and Other Papers.
  - WRITINGS
    - Autobiography, draft, typescript (photocopy), undated (Box 49, Folder 1549-1550)
    - "Bright intervals," draft, typescript (photocopy), undated (Box 49, Folder 1551)
    - "The flying clouds," draft, typescript (photocopy), undated (Box 49, Folder 1552)
    - "I talk to myself: the account of a journey through Europe between October 1956 and June 1957…" draft, typescript (photocopy), undated (Box 49, Folder 1553)
    - "Obiter scripta," draft, typescript (photocopy), undated (Box 49, Folder 1554)
    - "Poems," drafts, autograph manuscript (photocopies), undated (Box 49, Folder 1555)
    - Other writings, typescript, 1941, undated (Box 49, Folder 1556)
- Oversize, 1854-1940; 1.75; (1 box)
  Oversize is composed of materials from all series. The papers are arranged in an order consistent with that in the original series.
  - PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Personal correspondence, 1912, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1529)
  - FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Family correspondence, 1909 Sep (Box 48, Folder 1530)
  - WRITINGS
    - Hutchins Hapgood
      - Books